+91 7358863153

VIJAYAKUMAR

SENIOR NETWORK ENGINEER

vignesh8458@gmail.com

Chennai

PROFILE INFO

VIGNESH

As an experienced IT professional with over 6 years in the industry, I possess expertise in implementation, installation, management, and support of LAN, WAN, SaaS, laaS, cloud services (Azure, AWS, GCP), and cloud networking. I pride myself on staying up to date with the latest industry trends to provide topnotch solutions and support to clients. In my years of experience in full company IT infrastructure implementation, I have successfully set up and configured a of technologies, including variety FortiGate firewalls with HA, L3 switches, cabling, APs, servers, CCTV, access controllers, video walls, and rack installations.

And I have led Google Workspace to Microsoft migrations and migrating FortiGate firewall configurations from older models to newer models and FortiGate VM firewalls. The migration aimed to transfer existing settings and policies, ensuring a smooth transition and upgraded network security. implemented the full Microsoft suite, including M365, Azure VNet, Intune, app installation automation, and conditional access. With my strong technical skills, and project management abilities, I can deliver comprehensive IT solutions that improve productivity and drive success for any organization.

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Engineering - ECE 2012 - 2016 Sri Ramanujar Engineering College

Higher Secondary Course 2010 - 2012 St Joseph's Higher Secondary School

EXPERTISE

- IT Infrastructure
- Cloud Services (Azure, AWS, Cloudflare)
- Automation
- Network Security and Firewalls
- Network Monitoring and Analysis
- Server Configuration and Security
- IoT (blynk IoT)

EXPERIENCE

- Propeltech Labs India Pvt Ltd, Chennai (Formerly AciesInd Pvt Ltd) Senior Network Engineer | Feb 2021 - Present
- Madbee Mobility Solutions Pvt Ltd, Chennai Network Engineer | Jan 2020 - Jan 2021
- AciesInd Pvt Ltd. Chennai Network Engineer | Aug 2019 - Dec 2019
- Vernalis Engineering Software Pvt Ltd, Chennai Network Engineer | Feb 2017 - Jul 2019

COURSES

CCNA Dec 2016

Certified Cisco Network Administrator

A+ and N+ Sep 2016

Hardware and Networking

Udemy Courses

Networking, Microsoft, and Fortigate

AZ-900, SC-200, FortiGate, Intune, Active Directory, MS-500, PowerShell, and Python

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Networking	Switching & Routing, VLAN, SDWAN, Captive Portal, VTP, 802.1X, Wi-Fi Access, High Availability, Site to Site VPN, Client to Site VPN, Structured cabling
Microsoft And Azure	Administration of M365, Exchange, SharePoint, Azure AD, Azure Sentinel, Intune MDM, Defender, Conditional Access, Application Integration, PIM, PowerShell Scripting, SSO, VM, Blobs, Kubernetes.
Firewall	FortiGate(VM firewall with HA, 80E, 60E, 50E, 60D), PF sense, Cisco Meraki
Monitoring	Site 24x7, Azure Monitor, Azure Sentinel, AlienVault OSSIM, Nagios core
Cloudflare	CDN, WAF, Load balancer, DNS, Proxy, Domain, SSL, Insights, ZTNA
Virtualization	VMware ESXI (vCenter), XenCenter, Proxmox, VMware Workstation, Hyper-V, Virtual Box.
Antivirurs	Microsoft Defender, Symantec, BitDefender
Server Configuration	Active Directory, Ansible, Gitlab, Jenkins, Squid Proxy Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL, IIS, Apple Business Manager.
Containerization	Docker, Kubernetes
ІоТ	Raspberry Pi, Arduino, ESP8266, Blynk
Email Suite	Microsoft Exchange, Google Workspace, Zoho, GoDaddy,DKIM, DMARC
AWS	EC2, AWS AD, S3, IAM, Load Balancer, Monitor.
ManageEngine	Endpoint Central(formely Desktop central), SDP, MDM
Operating System	Windows Server OS, Windows 10 & 11, macOS, Ubuntu, Centos, Raspberry Pi OS.
CCTV And Access	Hikvision, CP PLUS, Matrix, Fortuna, EZVIZ
Ticketing	Zoho ManageEngine, Freshworks
Meeting Room Solution	Logitech, Poly, Ditto
WIFI AP	FortiGate AP (FortiAP), Ruckus, ZyXEL
Backup	iDrive, iperius, Clonezilla, AWS S3, Custom backup script
Purchasing	Negotiation skill, Purchase Server, Firewall, Switch, AP, Other peripherals, Vendor details.
NAS	WD, Sinology, Freenas

PROJECTS

• IT Infrastucture

In my current organization, I was responsible for setting up the entire IT infrastructure from scratch for the new office, including obtaining a WAN connection and purchasing and configuring network devices such as a firewall, L2 and L3 switches, rack servers, Wi-Fi APs, an NVR, access control, temperature and CO2 sensors, website hosting, and Azure AD with Intune and defender. I also developed PowerShell and shell scripts to automate endpoint optimization.

IT Monitoring

In my current organization, I configured Site24x7 monitoring services for servers, network devices, websites, WAN, public IPs, Docker containers, VMware vCenter and ESXI. I wrote a Python script using the Selenium module to automate the browser window for NOC display. In one screen, you can see multiple dashboards like server health, antivirus incident, firewall interface utilization, Intune compliance and etc.

Hosting With CDN

I configured production WordPress website with Cloudflare CDN to improve security and speed for global users. I also used Cloudflare WAF to block unwanted traffic and bots, and Cloudflare Loadbalancer to route SSL VPN traffic based on WAN health.

Cloud Environment

During my time at Acies during the COVID-19 pandemic, I migrated the entire IT infrastructure to AWS in a limited amount of time, including virtual machines, VM firewalls, load balancers, and servers.

IOT Project

When I was working at Madbee, I handled server management and some IoT projects, such as feedback devices, temperature monitoring, and SIM-based IoT devices.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars.

Date: SIGNATURE

Location : Chennai (Vignesh M V)